Preliminary Inventory to the Carl and Helen Winter Papers TAM.583
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- II, Correspondence
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Crockett, George, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Crockett, George, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Goodman, Ernest, Jun 6, 1952, Dec 8, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Winter, Carl: Telegram From Isserman, Abraham, Jul 27, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with McPhaul, Arthur (Michigan Civil Rights Congress), Jul 28, 1951, Aug 8, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Winter, Carl: Telegrams from Saypol, Irving (United States Attorney), Jun 28, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Weissberg, Simon, 1950-Dec 1951 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Weissberg, Simon, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Weissberg, Simon, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Weissberg, Simon, 1954-Feb 1955 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Oct 26, 1949, Feb 14, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen (and Michele Winter), Apr 1951-May 1951 (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jul 1951-Aug 1951 (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Sep 1951-Oct 1951 (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Nov 1951-Dec 1951 (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jan 1952-Feb 1952 (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Mar 1952-Apr 1952 (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, May 1952-Jun 1952 (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jul 1952-Aug 1952 (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Sep 1952-Oct 1952 (Box 3, Folder 155)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Nov 1952-Dec 1952 (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jan 1953-Feb 1953 (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Mar 1953-Apr 1953 (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, May 1953-Jun 1953 (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jul 1953-Aug 1953 (Box 3, Folder 160)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Sep 1953-Oct 1953 (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Nov 1953-Dec 1953 (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jan 1954-Feb 1954 (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Mar 1954-Apr 1954 (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, May 1954-Jun 1954 (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jul 1954-Aug 1954 (Box 3, Folder 166)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Sep 1954-Oct 1954 (Box 3, Folder 167)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Nov 1954-Dec 1954 (Box 3, Folder 168)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, Jan 1955-Feb 1955 (Box 3, Folder 169)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Helen (Typed Out Transcripts of Letters), Aug 1952-Aug 1953 (Box 3, Folder 170)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 171)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jul 1951-Dec 1951 (Box 4, Folder 172)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jan 1952-Jun 1952 (Box 3, Folder 173)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jul 1952-Dec 1952 (Box 3, Folder 174)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jan 1953-Jun 1953 (Box 3, Folder 175)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jul 1953-Dec 1953 (Box 3, Folder 176)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jan 1954-Jun 1954 (Box 3, Folder 177)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jul 1954-Dec 1954 (Box 4, Folder 178)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Jan 1955-Feb 1955 (Box 3, Folder 179)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winter, Michele, Undated (Box 4, Folder 180)
  - Winter, Carl: Letters and Postcards From Supporters, Sept 13, 1949-Sep 28, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 181)
  - Winter, Carl: Telegrams From Supporters (Includes George Crockett, Nat Ganley and Saul Wellman), Sep 1949-Oct 1949 (Box 3, Folder 182)
  - Winter, Carl: Holiday Cards (1), 1953 (Box 4)
  - Winter, Carl: Holiday Cards (2), 1953 (Box 4, Folder 184)
- III, Detroit Red Squad
  - Copies of Index Cards Summarizing Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, Apr 1945-Jan 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter: Biography and Photos (Prints and Photocopies), 1950s (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter: Photos of Demonstrations Outside Federal Building at Foley Square in New York City, Aug 15, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1945-1948, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Carl Winter, 1965-1971 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Copies of Index Cards Summarizing Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1948-1972 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1948-1951 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Detroit Police Department Red Squad Files on Helen Winter, 1965-1974 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation: File on Michele Stone (Michele Winter), 1965-1966, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- IV, Political Activities
  - "A Tribute To Ernest Goodman" (Program from Event), Dec 13, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Action! Motown '97 (Political Demonstration), Jun 1997 (Box 5)
  - Addington, Wendell Phillips: Memorial Program (Detroit Activist), Oct 1998 (Box 5)
  - AFL-CIO: Solidarity Day Certificate, Jan 18, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Allen, Ernesta: Obituary, Undated (Box 5)
  - Allison, Hortense: "A Day Of Bloodshed," Daily Worker, Sep 20, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Allison, Hortense: Acceptance of Lenin Centennial Memorial Medal (Draft of Speech), 1971 (Box 5)
  - Allison, Hortense: "Recalling A Seattle Soapbox," Daily Worker, Feb 22, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Allison, Hortense: Writings (Handwritten), Undated (Box 5)
  - Allison, Hortense: Writings (Typed), Undated (Box 5)
  - Alston, Christopher: Memorial Program (Detroit Activist), Apr 29, 1995 (Box 5)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, Metropolitan Detroit Branch: A Tribute to George W. Crockett Jr., Sep 1995 (Box 5)
  - Artt, Michele and Helen Winter: "Remembering Audrey" (Audrey West), Undated (Box 5)
  - Cain, Lee, Carl Reinstein, Stella Reinstein, Ethel Schwartz, Lasker Smith: 80th Birthday Dinner Tribute (Detroit Activists), Sep 21, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Center For Marxist Education: Charles And Margaret Krumbein Scholarship Fund, Undated (Box 5)
  - "Chain Letter To Ike" (Korean War), Circa 1952 (Box 5)
  - Cheprakov, V.: "Classes In Present Day Capitalist Society" (Translated From Communist No. 5, 1959), Apr 1960 (Box 5)
  - Chicago Committee To Defend The Bill Of Rights: Memo On Anti-Subversives Detail Of Chicago Police Department, Oct 2, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Clippings, General, 1956-1990s (Box 5)
  - Columbia College Chicago: Paul Robeson 100th Birthday Committee: "Paul Robeson Rediscovered: An Annontated Listing Of His Chicago History, 1921-1958", 2000 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party of Columbia: Printed Material, Typescripts and Clippings, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party of Michigan (Carl Winter): Press Release Protesting Police Treatment of Charles Gordy, Nov 1950 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party of Soviet Union: Press Release on Fifth Anniversary of 1969 International Meeting of Communist and Worker's Parties, Jun 5, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party of Venezuela: Typescript and Brochure, Undated (Box 5)
  - Communist Party of Washington State: Women's Committee Report (Hortense Allison), Circa 1969 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA: 25th National Convention: Pre-Convention Discussion Bulletins, Jul 1991-Oct 1991 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA: 25th National Convention: Pre-Convention Documents, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA: 25th National Convention: Pre-Convention Documents, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA: 25th National Convention: Press and Journal Coverage, Dec 1991 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA: 27th National Convention: Keynote Address by Sam Webb and Other Documents, 2001 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA: "Auto Industry and Political Economy" (Lesson Book), Jan 1957 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA: "C.I. Resolution on Negro Problem in US" (TS, 10 pp), Undated (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA (Carl Winter): Communist Party Standards (On Drug Use, Homosexuality, Morality), 1978-1985 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA: Draft Trade Union Program, Circa 1986 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA: Funds for the Future Campaign, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA: Michigan Hall-Davis-Webb-Frankia Campaign '84 Report, Nov 1984 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA: New Member Materials, Outline for New Member Orientation Meetings, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA: Second Extraordinary Conference: Keynote Report and Other Materials, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA Constitution Committee: Carl Winter's Notes On, Undated (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA Constitution Committee: Changes to Constitution Recommended for Adoption by the 24th National Convention, Circa 1990 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA Lecture and Information Bureau: "Marxism and the World Today" (Discussion Guide), 1960s (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA Political Bureau: "Political Bureau Resolution on Making a Turn in its Work", Jun 1981 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA Workers Circuit Schools: Notes for Teachers and Other Materials, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Communist Party USA Young Workers Liberation League: "Why Nixon Must Go!", Circa 1974 (Box 5)
  - Corvalan, Luis: Article in Nouvel Observateur (Transcription), Circa 1977 (Box 5)
  - Davidow, Mike: Memorial Program And Obituaries For, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Crockett, George: Memorial and Obituaries For, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Dennis, Eugene: "On Uniting and Strengthening the Party and its Mass Work" (Draft Resolution to National Committee of CPUSA), Circa 1958 (Box 5)
  - Dennis, Thomas: Memorial Program, Nov 15, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Detroit Urban League: Distinguished Warriors, 1985-1990 (Box 5)
  - Dewey, Hope: Memorial Program (Detroit Activist), 1996 (Box 5)
  - Economic Notes (Newsletter), 1980, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Fishman, Al and Marge: Community Tribute (Detroit Activists), Jun 10, 2001 (Box 5)
  - Ford Hunger March Memorial Committee: Receipt Book (Louis Leny), 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - Global Books Forum (Helen Winter): Invitation to a Latin Cabaret, Undated (Box 5)
  - Goodman, Ernest: "A Dialogue Between Gordon, an American Lawyer, and Petrovich, a Soviet Lawyer, at Moscow - 1963" (Proof and Final MS), Circa 1963 (Box 6)
  - Goodman, Ernest: "The Lion in Winter" (Profile in Detroit Free Press Magazine), Dec 8, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Hall, Gus: "Gus Hall Revisited," The Community Dispatch (Cherry, Minnesota), Jul 1999 (Box 6)
  - Hall, Gus: Memorial Program, Obituary, Remembrance by Helen Winter, Oct 2000-Nov 2000 (Box 5)
  - Hall, Gus: Student Questions From Speaking Tour With Notes by Carl Winter, 1960s (Box 5)
  - Hall, Gus: "The Communist Party USA - Changing, Growing, Swimming in the Mainstream" (Report to the National Committee of the CPUSA), Jan 17, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Hall, Gus and Henry Winston: Transcript of Soviet TV Interview With, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Hate Mail Sent to Carl and Helen Winter, 1961, Undated (Box 5)
  - Helsinki World Youth Festival, July 28-Aug 6, 1962: Report On (Box 5)
  - Jagan, Janet: Letter from Gus Hall, Clipping, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Jewish People, Draft Resolution on Work Among (Includes Contributions by Jack Kling, Hy Lumer and Carl Winter), 1960 (Box 5)
  - The Jewish Question: Clips and Ephemera (Soviet Anti-Semitism, Nazism), 1956-1962 (Box 5)
  - Johnson, Oakley C.: "Campus Battles for Freedom in the Thirties," The Centennial Review (Inscribed to Carl Winter), 1970 (Box 5)
  - Le Sueur, Marian: Memorial Booklet For, 1954 (Box 5)
  - "Life of the Party," City Pages (Profiles of Minnesota Communists Alma Foley, Meridel Le Sueur, Toini Mackie, and Helvi Savola), Oct 6, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Lumer, Hy [?]: Political Economy I Syllabus, Apr 1961 (Box 5)
  - Machado, Eduardo (Brother-in-law of Helen Winter): Clippings, Memorial, "Testamento Politico de Eduardo Machado" (In Spanish), 1960s-1996 (Box 5)
  - Machado, Gustavo (Brother of Eduardo Machado): Transcript of TV Interview with Machado on Communism in Venezuela, Circa 1963 (Box 5)
  - Mahaffey, Maryann: Programs from Tribute and Memorial, Obituaries For, 2006, Undated (Box 5)
  - Marxism-Leninism: An Introduction (Syllabus), Undated (Box 5)
  - Meyers, George: Eulogy For (Author Unknown), Circa 1999 (Box 5)
  - Meyers, George: "Better Red," Profile in Baltimore Sun (Inscribed by Meyers to Helen Winter), May 29, 1996 (Box 5)
  - "Michigan Militant" [Apparent Right Wing Group Calling for Death of Carl Winter and Other Michigan Radicals], 1964 (Box 5)
  - Michigan State Committee Communist Party: "Which Way to Peace" (Program Symposium on Events in Eastern Europe), Circa 1959 (Box 5)
  - Midwest Labor Institute for Social Studies: Announcements, Press Clip, 1988 (Box 5)
  - Miettuner, Leona: Obituary, Dec 24, 2000 (Box 5)
  - National Labor Youth League Conference: Proceedings of the Final Convention and Statement by Michigan Labor Youth League, 1957 (Box 5)
  - National Negro Labor Council: 40th Reunion Materials and "A History" by Mindy Thompson, Circa 1956, 1978, 1993 (Box 5)
  - "Peaceful Coexistence and the Ideological Struggle" (Editorial from Kommunist, no. 16), 1959 (Box 5)
  - Pollock, Sandy: Memorial Program, Remarks by Helen Winter and Letter to Sandy Pollock's Parents, Statement by CPUSA, Jan 1985-Feb 1985 (Box 5)
  - Progressive Youth Organizing Committee: Detroit Conference, June 17-18 1961: Resolutions (Box 5)
  - Reference Center for Marxist Studies: News, Fall 1992 (Box 5)
  - Russian Language Notes and Clippings, 1936, Undated (Box 5)
  - Schwartz, Ethel: A Celebration of Ethel Schwartz at 90 (Detroit Activist), Sep 9, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Segal, Edith: "Peace and Jobs for Peace: Unemployed Americans Speak" (Poem), Undated (Box 5)
  - Shapiro, Harold (Hal): Materials from Memorial and Obituary For, Sep 1999 (Box 5)
  - Smith, Lasker: "A Story Book About My Life" (Self Published Memoir by Detroit Activist), 2000s (Box 5)
  - Southern Conference Educational Fund: Memo Requesting Assistance for Rosa Parks in Detoir, Apr 17, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Tyner, Jarvis and Sam Webb: "James Jackson Jr. - An Appreciation", Sep 11, 2007 (Box 5)
  - United Nations: International Year of Mobilization for Sanctions Against South Africa, 1982 (Box 5)
  - U.S. Peace Council: A Detroit Tribute to Paul Robeson (With Transcript of Narration by Michele Stone Artt), Nov 14, 1987 (Box 6)
  - U.S. Peace Council: Memorial Letter for Bernie Barth, 2000 (Box 6)
  - U.S. Peace Council Michigan Chapter: Newsletter (Including Story by Helen Winter), 1984 (Box 6)
  - Wellman, Saul: Letter on Events in Eastern Europe and the Soviet Union, Apr 1990 (Box 6)
  - "What is a Marxist Lenninist Home Library?" (Stanley B. Ryerson), Circa 1950 (Box 6)
  - Whitty, Michael D. "A Labor Revolutionary in Detroit" (Nat Ganley), 1976 (Box 6)
  - Williamson, Mae: Memorial Program For, Nov 1977 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: "A Guide to the Fight for Jobs or Income," Daily World (Article on Organizing the Unemployed), Apr 21, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Clippings About, Circa 1940s-1960s (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: "Club Education Outline on Struggle Against Unemployment and for Organization of the Unemployed", Jun 1982 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Communist Party of Michigan: Press Release Protesting Police Treatment of Charles Gordy, Nov 1950 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Daily World Q & A Column, 1977-1980 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Draft of Essay on History of National Movement of the Unemployed and National Hunger Marches During the 1930s, Undated (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: "Great Decisions in Foreign Policy" (TS of Eight Essays), Spring 1963 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: "Historical Materialism and Class Struggle": Notes, 1960s (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to the Editor of the Detroit Free Press on McCarran Act and Kennedy Assassination, 1961, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Memo to Gus Hall with Comments on Hall's Report to Central Committee of CPUSA, Apr 19, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl (Michigan State Committee Communist Party): Letter to Supporters on Campaign Against Mundt-Nixon Bill and Callahan Act, Jun 1948 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl (Michigan State Committee Communist Party): "The Face of a Social Democrat: Walter Reuther" (TS), 1946 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: "Memo on Petrov Outline of Contents for Proposed Book on History of CPUSA", Circa 1970s (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Miscellaneous Notes and Fragments, 1981, Undated (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Nelson Mandela's Visit to Detroit: Guest Pass and Letter from Coleman Young Re: Anti-Apartheid Activists Reception, Jun 1990 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Notes and Syllabus for Class on Dialectical Materialism (National Training School), JUl 1981 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Notes for Lecture on Unemployed Workers Movement of the 1930s, May 1975 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: "Notes on a First Reading of Nemmy's Manuscript: 'Common Sense About Communism'" (Nemmy Sparks), Mar 1961 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Press Passes for Conventions and Rallies, 1958-1963, Undated (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: "Production Forces and Production Relations in USA" (Notes for Talk or Paper and Reference Note Cards), Circa 1934 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Readings on Communists and the Trade Unions (Lists for Class), 1980s (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Report to CPUSA on Trade Union Movement with Related Notes and Clippings, Dec 3, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Report to Michigan State Committee on Meeting of National Committee of CPUSA, Jun 5, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: "Soviet Union and Real Socialism": Lecture Notes for Class at Du Bois-Foster School of Marxism Leninism and Related Clip from Moscow News, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: "Speech to Colloquium, Arranged by Marxist Institute and Anti-Imperialist Bulletin of FRG", Oct 1978 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Speech to National Executive Board of CPUSA on Electoral Politics, Mass Movements and "New Politics" Movement, Apr 1968 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Statement of CPUSA in Advance of US-Soviet Summit, Circa 1959 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Statement to National Committee of CPUSA on Soviet Invasion of Czechoslovakia, Sep 1969 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: Teaching Materials for National School Class on Socialism, Circa 1972 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl [?]: Typed Excerpts from Political Histories by George F. Kennan and Charles Burton Marshall, Undated (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl: "What We Can Learn From the 1930s," Party Affairs (Re: Unemployment), Apr 1971 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl and Allan, William: Draft of an Article for the Michigan Daily Worker on Detroit Mayoral and City Council Elections, Nov 26, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Carl and Winter, Helen: Mailgram to President Reagan After the Film "The Day After" Protesting Nuclear Deployment (With Related Clip), Nov 1983-Dec 1983 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: 15th Anniversary of Global Books (Speech and Announcement), 1975 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Cards, 1970s, Undated (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Cards and Letter From Foreign Embassies and Individuals, 1971-1983, Undated (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Chicago Daily Worker Forum: Report on 25th Congress of CPUSA (Notebook and Other Materials), 1976 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Clip with Photograph of Helen Winter Leading the 1933 May Day Parade in New York City (Copy), Circa 1993 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Draft of Circular Letter for People's Weekly World, 1990s (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: "Ford Hunger March Inspired New Struggles," People's Weekly World (Book Review), Mar 14, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: International Conference for the Holding of Tripartite Talks for the Peace and Reunification of Korea: Conference Materials and Notes, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: "La Politica Exterior De Los Estados Unidos: Como Quisiera Que Fuera Los Trabajadores Norteamericanos" (Journal Article in Spanish), Circa 1970s (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Memorabilia from Trip to France for Congress of Parti Communiste Francais, May 1979 (Includes Photos) (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Message from the Communist Party, USA (On the Death of Ruth First, African National Congress), Oct 14, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Notes for Radio Moscow "Recollections", Feb 14, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Notes for Speech on Ed Teixeira's 50th Birthday, Circa 1982 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Notes for Speeches on Crisis in Poland and Related Materials, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Notes for Speeches on Peace Movement and Foreign Policy, Circa 1975-1981 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Notes from 25th Congress of the CPSU, Feb 1976-Mar 1976 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Notes from 25th National Convention of CPUSA, Dec 1991 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Notes from Conference in Sofia, Bulgaria and Questions from Radio Sofia on Georgi Dimitrov, Jun 1982 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Notes from CPUSA Conference in Washington, DC, Nov 1975 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Notes on CPUSA Meeting, Feb 15, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Notes on Meetings of Delegations of CPUSA and CPSU, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: Notes on National Alliance Against Racial and Political Repression Rally, April 30, 1993 (Includes Program), May 1, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Winter, Helen: "On the Observance of the 30th Anniversary of the Victory Over Fascism" ( Political Affairs or Party Affairs [?]), 1975 (Box 6)